Guide to the CITYarts Inc. Records 1969-2016 MS 3096
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Artwork, Miscellaneous Photographs, and Other Visual Materials, 1970s-2011; 11.5 Linear feet in 8 boxes of various size + 4 flat file folders
  - Drawing for "Young Minds Build Bridges" (oversize flat file), undated (Folder FF-2)
    From a collaboration between Family Academy in Harlem & Robert Schlom School.
  - Proposal for a composite photomural for Herald Square Station, by Claude Samton (oversize flat file), undated (Folder FF-3)
  - Drawings re: Louis Armstrong mural (oversize flat file), 1981 (Folder FF-4)
    Includes a blueline design drawing by Lucinda Luvass for both walls of the Louis Armstrong mural, and an oil on board painting of the mural. See also box 61 for smaller pieces related to this mural, each depicting the right or left wall only.
  - Various drawings (oversize flat file), undated (Folder FF-5)
    Includes drawings (crayon, pencil, pen & ink, watercolors) including, among others, Beach 116 Street Entrance for Rockaway Park, NY; "Nature of this flower is to bloom"; wall painting for Municipal Parking Lot #2, Astoria, Queens; etc.
- Series VI. Leslie Bender Artworks (RESTRICTED), circa 1981; .42 Linear feet
  The series includes several artworks drawn by Leslie Bender for Cityarts murals. Includes pencil, crayon, chalk, pastels, and other media. Bender was the artist for at least two Cityarts Workshop projects at schools in Queens (see Series I, projects 87 and 88) and the artworks in this series might be related to those.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The drawings are rolled and require preparatory conservation work before use. Please give advance notice of 3 days, in addition to the usual advance notice for offsite material.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Leslie Bender, 2020. The gift was not received as part of the CITYarts records donation, but was added to the finding aid by N-YHS staff because of the close connections of the content of the material.
  - Leslie Bender artworks (Restricted), circa 1981 (Offsite-box 60)